Hi, I'm Stan DeFreitas, "Mr. Green Thumb", for on gardening.
One most import parts of gardening mixes is peralite.
Now peralite is a material it's actually has been exploded at about 1800 degrees.
When you look at peralite, it's a very air like material, it's like popcorn.
When it gets exploded at 1800 degrees, there's really nothing there that's going to be detrimental to your plant.
There's no nematodes, there's no disease, because this material is sterile.
It also of course lets air flow through your soil, so it's great for starting rooting cuttings, or if you got it in your potting soils.
You'll notice almost every good gardening mix has got some peralite in it, and there's a reason for it.
If you want to be a good gardener, you're going to have to think about using peralite just like the pros do.
This is the reason that most of their cuttings live, because they're often starting off with a very sterile medium.
Remember, 1800 degrees, like popcorn, it's going to be a good mix and a good addition if you want to be a good gardener.
For On Gardening, I'm Stan DeFreitas, "Mr. Green Thumb".